Ladies and gentlemen, good evening and a
very warm welcome to the ICICI Lombard
General Insurance Company Limited's Q3
and 9month FY24 earnings conference
call.
From the senior management, we have with
us today Mr. Sanjie Mantri, MD and CEO
of the company. Mr. Gopal Balachandran,
CFO and CRO,
Mr. Mr. Aloc Agarwal, Executive
Director,
Mr. Girish Nyak, Chief Technology and
Health Underwriting and Claims and Mr.
Sep Gada, Chief Corporate Solutions
Group.
Please note that any statements or
comments are made in today's call that
may look like forward-looking statements
are based on information presently
available to the management and do not
constitute an indication of any future
performance as future involves risks and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from the current
views being expressed.
As a reminder, all participants lines
will be in the listenonly mode. There
will be an opportunity for you to ask
questions after the presentation
concludes.
Should you need assistance during this
conference, please signal an operator by
pressing star and then zero on your
touchstone phone.
I now hand the conference over to Mr.
Sanjie Mantri, MD and CEO of ICICI
Lombard General Insurance Limited. Thank
you and over to you sir. Thank you. Good
evening to each one of you. Thank you
for joining the earnings conference call
of ICL Lombard for quarter 3 and 9
months financial year 2024.
I would like to wish you and your family
a great 2024 ahead.
While we had a brief intraction in the
last quarter, I'm happy and excited to
engage with you all in my new role. I
would like to take the first few minutes
to share my vision on the journey ahead
for our company.
I firmly believe we're in the midst of
exciting times both as a country and as
an industry.
India is expected to be the fastest
growing economy globally. Insurance
sector is our is a country continues to
provide a multi-deadeal growth
opportunity supported by the regulatory
commitment to enable insurance for all
by 2047.
In my view, this will unleash tremendous
positives for the industry in time to
come.
As a company, we will continue to create
newer value pools in the industry and
maximize our participation in the
existing ones. And I believe we can
achieve this through our vision of one
is one team.
Now let me give you a brief perspective
on our vision of one team. Over the
years, the company has created multiple
functions seen
to access various of business
opportunities available. This was an
approach which worked well for us in
that phase of a journey. However, the
present scenario is fast evolving and
dynamic due to which the existing way of
functioning inhibits us from leveraging
the combined strength of the
organization. Keeping this in mind, we
have decided to bring a conscious shift
in a core philosophical approach. We a
we aim to transcend functional silos and
convert the entire organization into a
united team working towards a single
organizational purpose. Simply put, it
implies when ICS Lombard wins, everyone
wins. This will be a cold cultural
anchor and every decision that we take,
whether strategic or tactical, will be
guided by this. I'm excited to share
that we have already taken early steps
to align our organization to this in
letter and spirit.
However, as we embark on this journey,
we will continue to focus on market
opportunities and leverage our existing
distribution channel. We have over the
years followed a customercentric
approach and will continue with our
overarching philosophy of balancing
growth and profitability.
Let me now give you a brief overview of
the industry trends and developments
that we have witnessed in the past few
months. Suppose this our CFO Mr. Gopal
Valachan will share the financial
performance of the company for the
quarter and 9 months ended December
31st, 2023.
Domestic GDP grew by 7.6% 6% during
quarter ended September 30th, 2023,
indicating strong growth primarily
driven by the government infrastructure
push. Healthy balance sheets of banks
and corporates, improving business
sentiments and rise in public and
private capex should boost boost capex
activity going forward. Broader economic
activity indicators like GST collection,
eway bills generation, manufacturing
PMI, non-food credit growth indicate
robust demand in the economy. However,
the hedgments for domestic growth can
emerge from weak external demand, tight
financial conditions and geopolitical
tensions.
As we speak, India is globally the
fastest growing auto market and is the
third largest in terms of sales volume.
As per CM in 9 month 2024, new private
car sales continue to have robust growth
despite the higher base with over 3.1
million vehicles being sold mainly
driven by festive festive demands.
For 9 month
13.5 million two wheelers were sold also
held by uptick in rural demand for the
full year. The sales are expected to
cross pre-COVID levels.
For 9 months financial year 2024, 1.2
million commercial vehicles were sold.
This was driven by growth in Infra and
other core sectors.
Health insurance continued to deliver
robust growth, remaining the largest
contributor to overall industry premium.
The commercial lines of business
witnessed growth in the line with
commercial current market environment.
Further private and public capex
involves investment has led to robust
growth in the engineering line of
business. We expect the commercial line
segment to do well in the future on back
of war economic growth and capacity
creation.
Now speaking of the performance the
general insurance industry delivered a
yi growth gross direct premium income
growth of 14% for 9 month 2024 excluding
crop and market health the growth is at
15.2% 2% for the same period. Overall,
the combined ratio of the industry was
at 111.9%
for H1 2024
as against 112.2% for H1 2023 excluding
the impact of wage areas for the PSU
insurers.
Within the industry, the industry
combined ratio for motor business was
119.4 4 for H1 of 2024 as against 123.5
for H1 of 2023. While the increment in
combined ratio is directionally
positive, it continues to remain at
elevated levels. Further for 9 month,
the industry has witnessed three
catastrophic events which is expected to
have an impact on financial year 2024
industry combined ratio.
Moving to business impact for us in
quarter three and 9 months for 2024.
The company grew at 13.4% during Q3 of
2024 which was higher than the industry
growth of 12.3%.
For 9 months 2024, our growth was 16.5%
against the industry growth of 14%.
I will now speak about our performance
in key business segments during the
quarter ended 9 month financial year
2024.
In the commercial line of business, we
have developed strong capabilities on
the back of a unique distribution
franchise duly complicated comp
complemented by our value added
services. This based underwriting and
large and highly rated reinsurance
capacities. As a result, we have
consolidated our market position in this
business over the last decade. During
quarter 3 financial year 2024, we grew
at 12.5% as an industry growth of 13.3%.
For 9 months financial year 2024 we have
grown by 15.7% which was higher than the
industry average of 9.7%.
Motor as a category has always been a
focus area for us. As we speak for the
first 9 months we are the second largest
motor insurer for quarter 3. We achieved
an industryleading position in this
segment. We have a robust reserving
philosophy
which is demonstrated by our reserving
triangles and granular data for our
portfolio decisions.
We'll continue to leverage our strong
multi-distributional
structure which enables us to access the
market along with the best-in-class
claim servicing teams focusing on
superlative customer experience. For the
motor segment in quarter 3, we
registered a growth of 5.6% 6% as as
against industry growth of 10%. For 9
months financial year 2024 we grew at
7.1% as against the industry growth of
14.3%.
The growth in motor segment was aided by
strong growth in the new private car
segment which grew at 30% for 9 months.
Our two-wheer growth of 9 months 2024
was 14% which was higher than the CM
volume growth of 9.9%. As the rural
demand picks up, we hope to see the
trend continue.
The CV segment as we had mentioned in
our earlier call had no TP price high
for financial year 2024 and consequently
we focused on targeted portfolio
sourcing among the available value
pools. For 9 month 2024, our mix for
private car, two wheeler and CV stands
at 51.4, 27.8%
and 20.8% 8% respectively.
We also continue to build efficiency in
motor claims. In quarter 3 2024
through our preferred partner network,
we have been able to service 67% of our
agency and direct claims up from 51% in
quarter 3 financial year 2023.
We are excited about the opportunity in
the motor segment and will leverage all
our existing capabilities as one team to
carry the momentum in the coming
quarter. The health segment continued to
be the fastest growing segment for the
industry. We grew faster than the
industry both in Q3 and 9 months
registering a growth of 24.7% and 29.1%
respectively. Our health business,
retail health business grew in line with
the industry at 19.2% for 9 months 2024.
To create a sustainable portfolio, we
are focusing on preferred geography and
hire some insured. Our new business grew
at 24.5% during this period. Why we why
we would have liked to grow faster? We
will continue to invest by focusing on
preferred segment and new product
launches in the coming quarters.
On bank assurance, we have developed an
industryleading practice which continues
to be a strong pillar for our company.
Our bank assurance and key relationship
group grew at 13.6%
for the quarter and 21.5% for 9 month
2024.
We'll continue to deepine our existing
relationships by creating new value
streams which at the same time focusing
on acquiring new relationship within
this ICA
within this ICA group distribution view
at 19.9%
for quarter 3 and 16.9% for 9 monthstop
solution for all insurance and wellness
needs the ILA app has surpassed
surpassed 8.5 million user downloads
till We continue our growth momentum
with 1.6 million user downloads for the
quarter and during the quarter source
premium was over 100 billion sorry 1
million through this app registered a
3.2x increase y
digital business grew at 39.1% in
quarter 3 and 43% in 9 months and
constitute 6.6% and 5.8% 8% respectively
of overall business numbers. It would
continue to continue to be the key
growth driver for us. As I look ahead,
I'm personally very excited with this
opportunity and committed to creating
long-term sustainable value for all our
stakeholders.
Now, I would request Gup to take you
through the financial numbers for the
recently concluded quarters and 9
months. Thanks, Ajib and uh good evening
to all. I will now give you a brief
overview of the financial performance of
the recently concluded quarter and 9
months. We have uploaded the results
presentation on our website. You can
access it as we walk you through the
performance numbers. Gross direct
premium income of the company was at
rupees 187.03 billion in 9 months FI24
as against rupees 160.48 billion in 9
months FI23.
This was a growth of 16.5% which was
higher than the industry growth of 14%.
Excluding crop and mass health, GDPI
growth of the company was at 15.6%.
It was higher than the industry growth
of 15.2% in 9 months FI24.
GDP was at rupes 62.3 billion in Q3 FI24
as against rupes 54.93 billion in Q3
FI23, a growth of 13.4%.
This growth was higher than the industry
growth of 12.3%.
Excluding crop and mass sales, GDPI
growth was at 12% which was again higher
than the industry growth of 11.3% in 9
months FI.
Our GDP growth during the quarter was
primarily driven by growth in the
preferred segments. The overall GDP of
our property and casualty segment grew
by 12.5% at rupees 16 billion in Q3 FI24
as against rupees 14.22 billion in Q3
FI23.
On the retail side of the business, GDP
of the motor segment was at rupees 28.42
billion in Q3 FI24 as against rupes
26.91 billion in Q3 FI23 registering a
growth of 5.6%.
The advanced premium numbers was was at
rupes 33.04 billion at 31st December
2023 as against rupes 32.89 billion at
September 30 2023. GDP of the hill
segment was at rupes 13.79 billion in Q3
FI24 as against rupes 11.05 billion in
Q3 FI23 registering a growth of 24.7%.
Our agents which includes a point of
sale distribution count was 1 lak 25,88
as on December 31, 2023 up from 1 lak
22,461 as on September 30, 2023. GDP of
the retail health segment grew by 16.2%
during the quarter 3. Group health
segment grew by 27.2% during Q3 FI 24th
as against last year where we saw no
major catastrophic events during the
year. During this year we witnessed
three major catastrophes cyclone paper
joint north Indian floods and cyclone
machang. Our share of insured losses in
these cat events have been lower than
our natural market share. Resultantly
combined ratio was 103.7% for 9 months
FI24 as against 104.6% 6% for 9 months
FI23
excluding the impact of CAT losses of
rupees 1.37 billion in 9 months FI24 the
combined ratio was 102.6%.
Combined ratio was 103.6% in Q3 FI24 as
against 104.4%
in Q3 FI23
again excluding the impact of CAT losses
of.54 billion rupees in Q3 FI24 the
combined ratio was 102.3%.
Our investment assets rose to rupes
468.67 billion as at December 31, 2023
from rupes 453.12 billion as at
September 30, 2023. Our investment
leverage net of borrowings was 4.11
times as at 35th December 2023 as
against 4.07 times as at September 30
2023. Investment income was at rupees
25.96 billion in 9 months FI24 as
against rupees 21.6 6 billion in 9
months FI23. On a quarterly basis,
investment income was at rupees 8.38
billion in Q3 FI24 as against rupees
7.66 billion in Q3 FI23.
Our capital gains net of impairment on
investment assets stood at rupees 3.95
billion in 9 months FI24
as compared to rupees 2.94 billion in 9
months FI23.
Capital gains net of impairment
investment assets stood at rupees 1.08
08 billion in quarter 3 FI24 as against
1.52 billion rupees in Q3 FI23. Our
profit before tax grew by 20.6% at
rupees 18.55 57 billion in 9 months FI24
as against rupes 15.4 billion in 9
months FI23 whereas PBT grew by 23.3% at
rupees 5.74 billion in Q3 FI24 as
against rupes 4.65 billion in Q3 FI23.
Consequently, profit after tax grew by
8.3% at rupees 13.99 billion in 9 months
FI24 as against rupees 12.92 billion in
9 months FI23 excluding the impact of
tax reversal provision in quarter 2 of
FI23.
PAT grew by 20.2% in 9 months FI24.
PAT grew by 22.4% 4% at rupees 4.31
billion in Q3 FI24 up from rupees 3.53
billion in Q3 FI23. Return on average
equity was 17.1% in 9 months FI24 as
against 18.1% in 9 months FI23. The
return on equity average equity for
quarter 3 FI24 was 15.3%
as against 14.3% in Q3 FI23. Solveny
ratio was at 2.57 times at December 31,
2023 as against 2.59 times at September
30, 2023. This continued to be higher
than the regulatory minimum of 1.5
times. As I conclude, I would like to
reiterate we continue to stay focused on
driving profitable growth, sustainable
value creation, and safeguarding
interest of policy holders at all times.
I would like to thank you all for
attending this earnings call and we will
now be happy to take any questions that
you may have. Thank you.
Thank you. We will now begin the
question and answer session. Anyone who
wishes to ask a question may press star
and one on their touchtone telephone. If
you wish to withdraw yourself from the
question queue, you may press star and
two. Participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question. Ladies
and gentlemen, we will wait for a moment
while the question queue assembles.
The first question is from the line of
Kishan Runga from MK Global. Please go
ahead.
Kishan, your line has been unmuted. You
may proceed with your question.
Kishan Runa, your line has been unmuted.
As there's no response from the current
participant, we will proceed to the next
question which will be from the line of
Shrea Shivani
from CLSA. Please go ahead. Thank you
for the opportunity. Uh congratulation
on a good set of numbers. I have uh two
questions. Uh so firstly uh excluding
all the calamities that we have seen in
9 month your combined ratio has come at
1023%.
Right? And we had earlier given a
guidance to reach 102% by FI25 end. So
clearly a much better growth in new
vehicle sales has supported lower loss
ratios this year. uh so can you help us
understand what is your revised guidance
for the next year or next two years on
the combined ratio side given that uh we
know that you are currently investing in
the health portfolio and on technology
front etc. So that will be the first
question and the second question sir can
you quantify the loss ratio trend for
retail health and group health and uh
there have been some COVID cases uh in
the southern part of the country how
many cases do you have is it something
that we should be concerned about for
the fourth quarter for the next quarter
just trying to understand if there's yet
another thing that hits us in the next
quarter
okay uh I think uh thanks uh as far as
the uh combined issue guidance This is
concerned uh then uh Gopal will share
with you in detail the loss issues that
you're seeking on the retail as well as
the group health side. Uh uh clearly uh
we stick to the guideline of what we had
mentioned that we'll go to 102 over a
period of time. Uh in terms of revision
clearly from industry standpoint again
we are seeing uh ourselves reasonably
well. Uh but does this lead to make us
believe the guideline can go through a
change at this point? Uh we would say we
hold to this. We want to see this trend
holding up over next maybe a quarter or
two and then we'll come back to the
market if we believe there's a revision
uh to be done on that. Uh in terms of
retail and GS trending wise yes we have
seen uh improvement over what we had
seen over last quarter. Gopas will share
the numbers in detail. Yeah sure. So I
think uh so if you look at the uh this
is employer employee or let's say the
group health loss ratio for quarter
three of last year's that number was
98.9%.
This year quarter 3 that number stands
at about 93.1.
Uh on a 9 month basis the again the GHI
loss ratios for last year was 95.9%. 9
months of the current year that number
is at 95.8.
On retail indemnity again in the same
order Q3 last year was 68%.
Q3 this year is at 66%.
Uh this is pretty much in line with the
range that we have been talking about
which is in the range of between 65 to
70% is the threshold that we are
comfortable with on the retail indemnity
side and on the 9 month basis again
retail indemnity loss ratios last year
was at 65.2 this year we are at about
65.6%.
Uh so that's the breakdown in terms of
the loss ratio across different
segments. To your last point on uh COVID
claims uh intimations I think too early
at this point of time we don't see any
specific uh instances or any spikes that
we get to see. Uh obviously we will
watch for the development but nothing uh
at this point of time for us to call out
as of no cause of concern.
Okay. Sure. And the overall combined
ratio guidance I get it right that you
may get come back to us after a maybe a
quarter or two if there's any change in
the guidance. For now it's 102 102% for
FI25. Yeah. Yeah. Right now it's 102.
We're not seeing it but as I said uh
seeing how the the other quarter 4 goes
will come back probably by the year end.
Sure. Sure. This is useful. Thank you so
much. Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
The next question is from the line of
Sankit Goa from Aventus Spark. Please go
ahead.
Yeah. Yeah. Thank you for the
opportunity. Uh we we are seeing a
little better trend in motor especially
in the month of November and December
compared to the industry. So so just
wanted to understand that our strategy
with respect to motor has little changed
probably we are seeing little growth
coming back. Is it because of the
pricing environment changing or or we
believe we will be little more uh
aggressive or or more confident to do
more than than what we were doing in the
past. That's that's my first question
and and and on similar lines uh again
again in the third quarter if I see you
seems to have grown health retail health
especially at a lower rate compared to
the industry. I mean despite doing
investments um we we thought that you
will grow at at least 1.2 2 to 1.3x of
the industry. Your growth seems to be
broadly lower than the industry
marginally lower than industry. So so
just wanted to understand uh why is the
cautious stance being taken with respect
to on on health or or is it because of
the competition on retail health uh that
that's on growth and and and and just
just on on Gopal the question is motor
TP loss ratio. uh you see the number
seems to be again uh very good at around
62 um in third quarter or 65 in in 9
months. So, so typically we tend to uh
boost up the reserves in in fourth
quarter that historical trend suggests.
So, so, so is it a case that we will see
a similar trend or or you believe that
65% motor TP loss ratio reported for 9
months will will sustain for the entire
year and and similarly if you can
comment on on the motor OD2 whether
whether this is this is the number what
we are looking at 65.
Okay. Uh sir I will Gopal will come on
the TP part. I'll cover the motor what
is the trend that we are seeing and the
strategy going forward also on the
retail length in terms of the uh numbers
which are relatively subdued which I
also said uh in my initial comment that
definitely would have wanted to grow
faster than that. Uh first thing on the
motor uh I think we continue to be a
very uh you know competent and uh
relevant player. uh we saw in the past
also and we given that guidance that
whenever we see that kind of a market
share we shaved off it was more
conscious because the intensity
uh what we thought would get stabilized
did not happen. Uh so we had taken a
step back and let it flow the way it is.
Now we have seen some of our key
competitors who are ruling in have
started uh putting lot more method in
that madness and that has given us an
opportunity. That being said, uh quarter
3 typically has a tendency to have lot
more new sales in the season and there
we do uh end up with the structure that
we have having a lot more uh to you know
uh achieve as a team on motor overall on
market share but more importantly the
very critical trend which can highlight
to all of you is that uh y we had been
losing bit of a market share but for the
month of December we have gained a
market share of 10.7% 10.5 last year in
December so That trend uh is a critical
one and we are well placed in terms of
what we believe. If we see this uh
environment operating in a semblance we
will not participate in any uh uh crazy
hunt if that's what the market leads to
every reason to believe there will be a
bit more of semblance and in that
scenario we will see ourselves exerting
a lot more in quarter 4 in time to come.
So that's what we have on motor trend
broadly on the retail health subdued
number. Uh it's it's not something which
we are very uh you know worried but yes
we would have loved to grow faster. We
have taken certain calls in terms of
some issue which category of portfolio
rights because again if you know
whatever health book that we write it is
for a lifetime visibility technically
and we need to hold on to that customer.
We had sort of early trend which got us
concerned. That being said, our new book
has still grown at almost 25%. And we do
believe that in uh uh in time to come
with the sort of investment that we have
done with our human capital as well as
the product profile which will also
happen over next couple of quarters from
our side, we would be a potent force and
the and the mission that we have shared
is firmly on track. These are all
conscious calls which does not deter us
uh in terms of where we stand. Uh motor
TC I'll ask Gopal to answer uh in terms
of the details that we had shot. So Sit
uh my uh I think our response will
pretty much be on the lines is what I
have been talking even in the past uh
few uh earnings call. Um so the range
within which motor or loss ratios will
operate I think even last quarters we
have been talking about in the range of
60 to 65%. I think we pretty much stay
on course in terms of that part of the
range on the motor owned damage side.
That's largely because I think uh as an
organization we are kind of focusing a
lot more in so far as uh the claims
initiatives are concerned uh whether it
is in the context of uh the average
claim size etc etc and therefore to that
extent I think the range that we are
comfortable with on motor is in the
range of 60 to 65 on motor third party I
think as we keep saying uh again
quarterly numbers may not be the right
way to look at but even on a 9-month
basis I think the number for us stands
closer to about 25%
there collect I think the range that we
have talked about has been in the range
of 65 to 70% but that again will be a
function of what kind of a risk
selection that we do and the point that
Sanjiv made I think clearly as an
organization we are significantly
focusing on much more uh granularization
of data risk selection uh and so on and
so forth and therefore to that extent
the range that we would be kind of
looking at operating would be on the
third party side between 65 5 to 70%,
which is why on balance when you look at
motor in the aggregate that number
should be in the range of between 65 to
67%. Which if you look at the 9 month
numbers the motor at on an aggregate
basis the loss ratio stands at about 65%
for this year. So the range that we
would be comfortable will be between 65
to 67 on on an aggregate basis. uh the
only point I would say is uh in so far
as there is no specific trend line for
us in so far as Q4 being seeing any any
form of abrasion I think possibly what
you're referring to is maybe couple of
years back uh this is I think financial
year 2021 if I recollect it correct I
think there was certain court supreme
court judgments that had come through in
that particular year and that's the
reason why not just for ISIS Lombard
even at an industry level companies had
to recalibrate their uh ultimate loss
experiences and therefore to that extent
one had to take some impact of uh
strengthening of uh losses but otherwise
it is not it is not necessary that uh we
do see any kind of an inch up in so far
as third party loss experiences are
concerned so far as quarter 4 uh which
you are referring to okay no no because
I I saw a similar trend in fourth
quarter 232 so so that's the reason I
was asking the question that that 65
number is sustainable but you answered
that you are looking at a broad number
of 65 to 72 to to play out for the motor
velocation. But yeah, Sanji just just uh
just to your comment on motor
just wanted to understand you are saying
that in market overall market
competitive environment in motor OD the
relative madness has has come off and
and therefore market is more conducive
than it was in the past. That's the
conclusion I should make. So I tell you
I think that will be a relatively
sharper conclusion but yes we do see
some of uh semblance uh overall and the
LR of the industry has gone on from 93
to 87 and
uh so that is the indication yes there's
a improvement but still if you ask me
from an overall standpoint uh the
industry is writing the motor portfolio
uh at a you know reasonable triple digit
of 1890. So there is a lot more that has
to come off. Uh and even a private
sector is writing at 114 115. Uh it's a
it's a long journey. Uh but what I can
tell you some is that where we stand the
lens through which we are looking at the
market we are reasonably confident of
our practice and we will be able to
drive value for the organization uh uh
in the current environment that is
failing. Uh but long-term trends have to
manifest. you know that the industry
numbers come with a lag. Uh we are
awaiting uh the 9 month numbers for the
industry to get a sense which will be
able to give you uh uh closer to when
the financial year gets close for us. At
that point of time we can have a much
more evolved discussion on this again.
Perfect. Perfect. That's it for my thank
you. Thank you. Thank
you ladies and gentlemen. in order that
the management can answer questions from
all participants in the queue. We
request you to please restrict your
questions to two per participant.
The next question is from the line of
Madukar Lada from Noama Wealth. Please
go ahead. Uh hi, good evening. Uh thank
you for this opportunity and
congratulations for a good actually
underwriting performance. Uh clearly uh
your you seem to be achieving uh your
guidance uh sooner than expected. Um so
just uh uh you know a couple of
questions uh on the motor side. So I
wanted to understand uh with how is the
implementation of the entire loss
reporting uh within 6 months time uh
time period uh how is that progressing
and uh uh you know uh what is our sort
of expectation on that and related
question on this is uh is the industry
um you know in this u uh sort believing
that this will get implemented and as a
result of that the competitive intensity
had had been high or uh or are they sort
of looking because you know they believe
that the ultimate loss ratios will be
lower. So is that uh is that the correct
way to think about it or is that the way
some industry participants are thinking
about it and acting in in in that way?
And second question on your investment
yield that seems to have dropped this
quarter. So some understanding of what
has actually played out over there. So
uh those two would be my questions.
Yeah. Thanks. Sure. So I'll uh I'll let
goal come in and I'll give my comments.
Yeah. Go. Go ahead. Yeah. So so Maduk I
think on the 6 months law of uh
limitation uh I think as we have been
kind of uh indicating that matters still
is before the Supreme Court and
obviously we will wait for let's say the
verdict to come out. What we understand
is I think most of the states seems to
be in favor of getting the law of 6
months implemented and therefore to that
extent I think one would obviously wait
and see how the final verdict plays
through but the the direction that
states want to take is clearly to kind
of get a law of limitation in place. Uh
having said that what could happen let's
assume for a moment that if it goes in
favor of let's say in line with the 6
months law of limitation again the
impact could vary between players in the
market because at an aggregate level for
the market obviously there will be some
reduction in frequency as we have been
explaining consequent to reduction in
possible frauds so that's a positive in
so far as the overall market is
concerned second I think in in in the
context of ICS Lombard obviously we have
been inflating uh reserves with an
inflation assumption for ISIS at between
12 to 13%. This inflation assumption for
the market may not be the same and
therefore to that extent whenever this
will play out the impact could be
slightly more beneficial for companies
which have been reasonable in their
inflation estimations and for us as I
said we ISIS Lombard has been inflating
at 12 13%. Market if they have been
inflating at a slightly lower number
therefore to that extent the impact
could be relatively moderate for those
set of players. So hence in that sense I
think it would obviously translate into
an incremental business opportunity for
us. Having said that this law of 6
months limitation will be applicable
only on a prospective basis which is
effective from April 1, 2022. So hence
to that extent uh is where we would be
able to see as I said a relative benefit
play out for us in the context of the
market. Uh the other thing what could
also happen as a flip side to this is in
case if finally this law gets
implemented there is a possibility that
next year or maybe in future the
regulator and the government will very
closely watch for the need for any kind
of a TP price increase. uh while last 3
four years again we have not necessarily
seen any kind of a meaningful price
change on the third party side but given
the fact that this this 6 months lock
could lead to a positive development
from an overall industry standpoint we
may see periods where we may not able to
see further increases on the third party
pricing but obviously that's a
development that we will again closely
watch for in so far as the third party
uh 6 months law of limitation dynamics
is concerned I'll quickly answer the
second question of yours and then maybe
Maybe Sanjiv if you want to kind of add
on. Uh so on the investment uh yield
again uh Modukar I think as we have
always said our realized return is a
function of what do we see as uh
interest approvals and uh what what is
it that we see as capital gains for us
uh given the fact that we have been
significantly as we've been explaining
even in the earlier earnings calls the
high interest rate regime is something
that we have obviously taken advantage
of and hence to that extent if you would
have seen our yield to maturity on the
overall book that currently in fact at
December 31 stands at 7.31%.
This number if you recolct maybe a
couple of few quarters back this number
was less than 7% at about 6.92%. So
hence to that extent we have actually
been taking uh advantage of the higher
interest rate regime and that's kind of
auguring well in so far as interest
approvals are concerned where you may
possibly see in some quarters possibly a
decline in yield is consequent to let's
say maybe relatively lower levels of
capital gains that's purely a function
of what we believe are market
opportunities for any gains to be
realized. We have generally not seen any
instance where we have seen uniform
levels of capital gains across quarters.
So in fact there again I would urge
similar to the discussions that we have
been having on having on the loss ratio
side the yield on the overall portfolio
should be looked at again ideally over
on a financialized basis ideally over
longer years but definitely not on a
quarteronquarter basis. So okay just to
add mukar in terms of the point that you
had mentioned on PP uh directionally and
we all will agree that even when became
part of motor vehicle act the adoption
at the state level would have always
gone through its source but if the
intent is to make the uh overall
consumer benefit these things in spite
of the hiccups I believe over a period
of time will get implemented uh in a
country like ours it will always be a
little more complex uh but multiple
decisions which have been taken by the
body we remain positively cautious and
see that this will flow in that
direction over a period of time. But one
bigger thing which I want to add Madukar
is the way III has come up the stream
and improved the quality of data sharing
that can happen at the industry level.
Uh that part uh has been transformative
and the level of accuracy and the the
real time manner in which we can think
uh all of the industry will benefit and
be with the uh with the level of you
know business that we do and that kind
of an accuracy. I mean you know that
banking got transformed when bureau came
into place and uh you could really
figure out where what stands and this
data uh once it gets created in the form
will also end up you know helping us uh
figuring out uh you know fraud and so on
and so forth. So the base work has got
done uh to me that is also a big
positive which can benefit companies
like us substantially uh to drive
efficient acquisition in the market.
Thank you.
Understood. Just one question on the U
investment book. Uh what is the amount
of capital gains
this time around? Uh if you could give
that versus the last quarter.
Uh the number of capital gains for the
quarter three was about 108 crores. That
is in that is in quarter three of this
year as against 152 crores which was the
capital gains that we had in quarter 3
of the last financial year. And last
quarter what was the number? Sorry.
Quarter two numbers uh of capital gain
that number was about uh
164 crores.
Okay. Understood.
Uh very clear. Thank you and all the
best. Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you. The next question is from the
line of Pesh Jen from Motila Lwal.
Please go ahead. Uh yeah. Hi, good
evening everyone. Uh just a few
questions. Firstly,
could you elaborate on your strategy
that you were talking about in our
initial opening remarks? U could you
just elaborate on that new philosophy
that you were talking about?
Yeah. Okay. Fair enough. I'll do that.
You have second question also you want
to say now which we can cover or we'll
come back once I reply on this. No. The
second question was more on motor motor
business granularity as to you know
we've seen uh you know faster premium
growth with respect to as compared to
the vehicle growth uh and that's
possibly because of certain factors like
premiumization share of EVs going higher
CNG share going higher top models going
higher or you know automated vehicles
going higher uh any of these cohorts
where you think that the you know
particularly EVs
where you know your experience would
have been kind of uh uh you know much
better than what you would have expected
earlier and you see some price
corrections out there or in with respect
to you know uh drive as you use or the
the the private project that we were
working on earlier how is that mix
evolving I think some granularity on the
motor business will help us kind of look
forward into the future on on this
business and last question was on
commission ratio
where you know how do you see the
commission ratio kind of panning out
this quarter it was at 17% thereabouts
and so how do you look at this ratio
from a full year perspective uh in this
year as well as years yeah okay okay
thanks P I think let me just give you a
quick perspective one team uh I think as
I also mentioned when I spoke earlier in
my script uh the fact that it's a core
philosophy change uh we've been in the
business for last 22 years and obviously
as an organization we have created
multiple center of excellencies. Uh and
these departments have gone on to
deliver a lot more for the organization
than one could have thought at the
inception level. Uh but the time has
come where we need to at an overarching
level uh see that we're able to derive
value uh at a multiplier level uh for
the organization. To give you an example
right we we had value added services
which was being driven by us as a
company. We have our own patents which
are registered uh to manage risk. But
this value services used to work more on
a project basis with the entities. What
we have ensured is that we getting this
embedded with the organization and
multiple departments on the commercial
side to drive the impact. Uh another
part is on the data analytics side you
know the data engineers we do we do have
that particular department which was
running and quite effectively but it was
not embedded. They used to operate on a
project basis. what we have done is that
we've gone ahead and got that department
uh working with business teams with
direct reporting in terms of making it
work. So there's lot of synergy benefits
that can be driven on this. Uh at
multiple counts we would be driving and
cross leveraging it. Uh our practice as
we have always mentioned on the
corporate side has been very extensive
but our ability to harness to even
procure retail business becomes a
significant part of our strategy. It's
not even cross- cell. It's actually all
embedded solution. The bulk of the
products that we deal with are uh you
know naturally inclined towards type
requirement whether it'smemes on the
commercial side or motor health is the
only discretionary product uh that
corporates indulge in. You will also see
product launches in time to come which
would be harnessing this opportunity
across the segment. you've large you've
got large presence for the consolidated
uh approach that was required mind you
but the word of caution is it does not
mean that the dissecting of the market
and ensuring that the leverage on our
distribution will get diluted uh at any
point on time for us so that's my two
bit in terms of you know discussing one
uh one team as a as a company now coming
on to the motor part of the strategy as
you see uh uh we have seen a significant
uh uh transformation uh I'll just cover
the EV part of business which you spoke
about uh from an overall industry
penetration level uh it has moved 9
month the penetration was 3.5 it's gone
to almost 4.2 uh uh% for us uh we as a
company have a very dominant share on
the EV side on the private car which is
the passengers car we're talking about
we have a market share of almost 18% and
on two-heer we have a market share of
almost 28%.
uh we are obviously bullish and we do
believe that over next couple of years
we will have the inflection point as the
infrastructure which is required to see
this uh getting much more uh so two
points one infrastructure other the
price point which makes it workable
we would continue to invest and uh loss
issue yes we do see that uh it's
relatively better but I would not rush
to conclude that as yet because these
are very early is this will emanate over
a period of time. Uh but we'll stay
invested because this is the category
which can rule the market. In terms of
overall motor uh clearly quarter three
new sales which you spoke about and
you've read those numbers that we have
seen a growth in private car of 30% in
two wheeler by almost 14% much higher
than what the industry has done. uh uh
again uh multiple things uh one we are
well equipped uh in terms of the new
business as in when that growth comes
back our ability to operate in a
decisive manner uh is pretty much there
existing and uh we do uh uh believe that
uh this should exhibit over next uh
probably a quarter or so also but we
never expected the industry on the
private car to grow at a level of almost
7 7 and a half% because the base last
year itself was high. Uh and India has
moved on to become the third largest
manufacturer of uh you know overall
motor vehicles which itself I think
speaks about how the volumes are getting
driven. Another big change which has
happened is the SUV cars have started
dominating which is the average ticket
size is high. So you would also see that
getting exhibited in a number uh as we
speak about the motor growth that will
come in. Overall we remain uh positive
in terms of guiding our motor initiative
uh as a team. Uh on the commission ratio
I'll ask Gopal to just quickly give you
an update. We've been pretty much within
the regulatory limit uh as prescribed
and quarter three since the new vehicles
are there the expense ratio tends to be
elevated historically for the industry
and more so for us. So pre I think again
uh in line with what we have been
mentioning even in the earlier earnings
call I think a better metric to look at
as we keep saying is combined ratios
because there will always be businesses
which could be high on LR and low on
cost of acquisition and the vice versa
as well. Uh so hence to that extent I
think one would urge uh to continue to
look at more the uh combined ratios of
the company as a whole. Having said
that, I think in line with what Sanjiv
said, if you look at our expense of
management numbers at the percentage of
GWP, uh this number for the 9 months
last year was at about 28.6%. For the 9
months of current year, this number
stands at about 28.1%.
So there has been some improvement in
the overall expense of management
numbers. But as I said, a better metric
to look at is more the command ratios
for the company as a whole. Uh this is
this commission ratio. We request you to
please rejoin the question queue for
further questions.
The next question is from the line of
Anidesh from Invest. Please go ahead.
Uh thanks for the opportunity sir.
Firstly of the health insurance uh we
have been investing in that uh uh
distribution uh for last uh almost two
years. Uh but still our growth has been
broadly in line with industry or uh in
the month of December we lagged
industry. uh so uh what are the
aspirations there and when we think uh
the the growth pick up in the retail
health concerns will be in our numbers.
Yeah I think a very valid question nit
again uh as I was mentioning given when
I was uh talking earlier in the call uh
we also uh would have prefer going
faster. Uh if you see our growth in
quarter one was uh quite higher than the
industry but we have taken certain calls
on the sum insured as well as the you
know uh nature of new business that we
want to procure. These were very finite
definite calls. We are very much on
track in terms of uh what we want to
achieve. Uh our new business of those
call has grown by almost 25% uh as a
company. So uh if you ask me where will
we see a real uh you know growth coming
in this since this changes have been
done over quarter one and quarter two.
You will see this playing out uh uh very
clearly over next financial year and
what we had spoken with the market at
probably three quarters back in terms of
the growth at that point these
calibrations that we have done because
we felt health as a portfolio which
comes with lifetime visibility requires
realtime calibration. So we chose to
take that call at this point of time so
that the long-term value creation that
we want for the organization does not
get compromised. uh but you will see our
convergence as a team not only in terms
of growth but also product launches uh
which are still uh if you ask us on a
score of 10 on product you know or
solutioning stack that we want to create
on the health side we would probably be
six and a half uh and thereabouts over
10 uh as a score. So we have that
distance to be covered and that also
will get done in next couple of
quarters. So we are very positive and we
do see uh a good value creation coming
uh from next financial year onwards.
Does that answer your question? Yeah.
Yeah. So secondly on the motor side our
profitability has improved quite well
and our loss ratios are tracking uh one
of the best that we have seen. uh so why
don't we pedal we push the pedal on the
growth and uh start focusing on market
share gains in that segment even the
profitability is quite good for us I
think you have only answered the
question uh in terms of we we will we
stayed focused and we had some losses on
market share but we we decided to stick
the course and that's what we are doing
at this point of time uh some of the
other partners who were uh you know
being aggressive have also cooled down
so it's a combination of we sticking to
the course and as I was also stating uh
that December was the first month in
which we have seen uh relatively better
market share in our mind uh we do
believe that quarter 4 should hold good
for us as a team.
Okay. Thank you. Thank you. That's just
my Thank you Nish. Thank you. Thank you.
The next question is from the line of
Ain Singh from MK Global. Please go
ahead. Yeah. Uh good evening. Uh couple
of questions. Uh the first one on
commercial line I mean fire marine
engineering if I look uh on a 9month
basis uh the movement YUI in claims
ratio is material. Now uh in terms of
NATCAT it would have kind of a played
out maybe a bit higher this year but not
material. So now just question is that
is this sort of a claim is increase in
the commercial line and outcome of you
know uh any sort of a pricing uh
deterioration at the industry level or
is it also or largely due to the
reinsurance price hike that industry has
seen. I mean some color on what is
driving this commercial uh uh line loss
ratio increase and if the factors that I
just mentioned you know the pricing
deterioration or resource price hike if
they are largely done this year and
should improve going forward next year
that's one second again going on health
you have I mean overall growth is
reasonably good uh growth is of course
led by the pricing as well as uh some
kind of a volume growth. Yet uh the
claims ratio at the aggregate level of
course if you go segment by segment
there could be some difference but at a
aggregate level claims is still inching
up. Now is this an outcome of you know
just the claims inflation or also you
know uh claims frequency also sort of
reflecting some kind of a uh increase
year on year. So two question. Thank
you. Yeah. Yeah. So, uh, Avin, uh, um, I
think on the first one on the commercial
lines, uh, pretty much in line with what
you mentioned, which is primarily
whatever you see as change in the loss
ratios whether it is for fire
engineering or some of the key
commercial lines. The large part of the
change in the loss experience is
predominantly driven by the impact that
we have seen on account of flood events.
uh so so and this year unfortunately if
you would have seen which is what we put
out also as a part of the opening
transcript I think the aggregate impact
that we have seen on account of various
catastrophic events last year was about
28 crores this year if you look at 9
months we are already that number is at
about 137 crores a large part of it is
of course some of the commercial lines
but maybe the recent Chennai floods I
would also say we have also got a
reasonably large number of claims that
is coming on the retail side which is on
the
uh side of the business as well. But to
stay with on the commercial lines, I
think the a large part of the the loss
ratio change is predominantly driven by
the impact that we have seen on account
of uh the various flood events that we
have seen and not because of uh any
other reason. In fact, uh the overall
growth in the commercial lines
particularly on fire has pretty much
played out in line with what we have
been seeing even in the earlier quarters
as in to say that the price drop
consequent to the removal of the IIB
rates has been broadly in that range of
5 to 7%. And which was largely offset I
would say by the increase in the
reinsurance rates that we had seen at
the time of negotiating the program at
the beginning of the year. So hence to
that extent is where I think our the
growth for the overall market has been
largely muted in line with what we spoke
even during the April call. uh what will
happen in the next year's reinsurance
renewal program. I think uh maybe I
think we will be able to come back with
a much better insight when we announce
numbers on a full year basis in April
because that's the time when we would
have largely concluded the reinsurance
placements but otherwise on so far as
the attritional losses are concerned I
think there is nothing other than some
of the impact on catastrophic losses
uh related numbers to your second point
on the health loss ratio I think it's
it's pretty much which is why I think in
response to one of the earlier uh
earlier questions that had come through
is where we kind of put out the
breakdown of the loss ratios. uh so so
in that sense there if you clearly see I
think the loss ratios are pretty much in
line with the range that we are
comfortable with which is just to kind
of reiterate group health loss ratios we
have generally talk spoken about it
being in the range of 94 95% that's the
number at which we have ended even the
current 9 month numbers and retail
health indemnity I think the range that
we have spoken about has been between 65
to 70% if you would have looked at the
9month numbers again they're pretty much
in line with the range that we have
spoken about Um, of course we do see
inflation
uh uh and let's say possibly at times
increase in claim frequency particularly
let's say during quarter 2 largely
driven by monsoons and other related
seasonalities but that's something again
like what I mentioned on motor where we
actively engage in kind of driving the
PPN initiatives uh on the motor side for
example we would obviously want to drive
a large part of the motor accidents to a
preferred network of garages The same
thought process is what we have even on
the health side which is to kind of we
have a separate network management team
which significantly looks at focusing on
driving a lot more traffic to a
preferred network of hospitals where we
are not only able to guarantee so far as
the policy holders are concerned quality
of care which is very very important for
us and more importantly an outcome which
is let's say a possible reduction in the
average claim size and thereby which is
how we are able to kind of manage the
possible change that we see on
inflation/ hash uh frequency and but on
an overall basis I think we're
comfortable at the range at which the
loss experiences is playing out
okay thank you
thank you
the next question is from the line of
supraatim data from ambit capital please
go ahead
thanks for the opportunity my first
question is on the new strategy of one
team so could you help me understand
what would be the impact act on the top
line from this strategy and what would
be the would this also have a cost
impact in the form of cost savings.
That's my first question. My second
question is on the reinsurance. So
globally if we see the reinsurance rates
uh you know this year at first has gone
up somewhere between 30 to 50%. what are
we expecting here in India given F you
know CY23 saw a little number of NATCAT
events which were higher than what we
had seen in CY22 so uh that's my second
question and lastly I would just like to
understand currently that now that you
know the growth has returned on the
motor side what is the market share that
you have now within you know the uh
private car segment or the two-heer
segment and the commercial vehicle
segment if you would help me with that.
Thank you. Okay. Sure. So on the uh one
team part in terms of the top line as
well as the cost I think it will get
embedded in a what Gopal said the
combined issue and what we are able to
deliver as a team. Uh uh we have taken
certain initiations in terms of what we
have done structurally but uh it may be
early days for us to quantify anything
of that uh to the market. you will see
that getting exhibited in time to come.
We believe that we rather do it than
announce that this is what we believe uh
will get transpired. Uh but clearly what
I can assure you is we do believe there
is a kicker available as on the top line
as well as bottom line on account of
what we are pursuing as a team. So
that's where it is and the reinsurance
part uh I'll ask Gopal to just give an
update. We don't expect the premiums to
run away. We do have a guideline where
we say 5 to 7 7 and a half% there about
is what you expect to come in but it
will all get probably called out in
specific over quarter 4. Uh Gop. Yeah.
Yeah. So I think uh just to kind of
subraim uh I think as I said uh so I
think we are in the midst of uh the
negotiations in so far as renewing the
reinsurance program is concerned and as
I mentioned I think we will be able to
give you a much better insight when we
kind of announce numbers for the April
uh April call uh is when we would have
stitched in the reinsurance uh program
and the rates for the next year but the
initial indication seems to kind of
unlike last year where we had seen a
significant increase in the cost of
insurance for protecting the uh the uh
net retentions or let's say the XL cost
that we have seen for protecting
catastrophic uh event related losses.
Our sense is obviously the hike may not
be as much as what we had seen last
year. Exact numbers I think as I said I
will come we will be able to come back
and give you much better clarity when we
announce numbers in April. That's on the
reinsurance side. To your point on uh
market share within let's say the new
market share for private car and uh two
wheelers private car we have a market
share of roughly about 12% around uh
that range and on two wheelers uh the
new market share has been uh currently
in the range of about 22%. This of
course is slightly lower than what we
would have normally had. I mean in the
past maybe our market share could on the
private car side would have been higher
by almost about 3 4%. And even on two
wheeler almost at a similar level I mean
you would have been we have always been
saying that on on new two wheelers one
in four uh one in four two wheeler sales
it's a it's a policy of prices. So to
that extent this is pretty much in line
with what we have seen over the last two
years where we have lost a market share.
But as Sanjiv indicated, I think the
momentum for us as we speak looks to be
very very strong and positive and which
is why if you look at some of the
quarter three or month of December
numbers, the head start that we're
getting into in Q4 and thereafter seems
to be very very positive for us and
that's what we are very optimistic and
hence to that extent uh even in the
earlier earnings call if you recollect
what we had said was uh motor we should
see on an aggregate basis growth coming
back uh in line with the market the
early trend seems to indicate that in
fact for the month of December just to
reiterate we have actually had an
outperformance relative to the industry
growth of 8.8%.
Thank you. Yes.
Thank you
ladies and gentlemen. Due to posity of
time we will now take the last question
from the line of Ashish Sharma from Anam
Asset Management Company. Please go
ahead. Yeah. Hi. Uh thanks for the
opportunity. Uh uh just one question uh
on on similarly on the combined ratio uh
given that we are trending better than
uh uh uh uh in terms of improvement in
combined ratio uh so can I mean if if as
you mentioned that you will take another
quarter or so before you would want to
change the guidance but just wondering
now is there a possibility now that the
business can operate at a combined ratio
of 100% or below I mean uh given that we
are seeing some sort of a
So uh I think fair question Ashish from
your perspective but I think stand uh
one could we'll discuss this further by
next as to where we are seeing because
we still want the uh overall trend
coming out in a consolidated we don't
want to jump the gun while the early
signs do look better for us but the sort
of opportunity that we have as a company
we will continue to invest uh so I would
be very honest uh that uh size invest
ment we can be where we are but uh and
the industry combined overall is still
at 112%. So you know there are
structural changes and my firm belief is
which I can share with you uh we would
love to see industry itself improving in
a significant way because today well
industry varies we are able to perform
at X if the whole industry improves
structurally I don't see any reason why
IC umbart can drive far better benefit
out of it so we are operating both
industry level as well as the company
level uh to make an impact uh but uh for
a company like us and the opportunity uh
which I said in my opening remarks again
is significant. So we would definitely
use some percentage of what comes our
way to reinvest uh to ensure that we are
future ready in terms of the opportunity
that comes. Uh would not jump the gun to
call out and say 100 is what it is. It
will be a mix of things. Health will
continue to seek more investment from us
because uh we have reasonable
competition as well as opportunities you
know being made available to us. uh and
similarly on the digital space we'll
continue to do what is required to
harness our own uh ambition of where we
want to be. So with all that in mind uh
uh I don't want to you know close out
simply that is what it would be but uh
let's discuss this when we are there on
the April in the call.
Thank you. Yes. Yeah. Ladies and
gentlemen, due to posity of time, that
would be the last question for today, I
now hand the conference over to Mr.
Sanjie Mantri for closing comments. Over
to you, sir. Uh I think uh thanks so
much. I think uh the call has gone
beyond the distance but absolutely enjoy
interacting with each one of you and
look forward to uh uh catching up with
each one of you in time to come. We stay
positive and we do believe that we have
a great set of colleagues operating in
this segment with very very extensive
experience and we would definitely do
what is required to you know add further
value to the company uh in terms of the
industry which gives us tremendous
opportunity. Thank you so much and have
a great 2024 and see you soon.
Thank you on behalf of ICICI Lombard
General Insurance Company Limited. That
concludes this conference. Thank you all
for joining us. You may now disconnect
your lines.